traveladnetwork.com 2010-06-12

# www.traveladnetwork.com - Privacy Policy

## Travel Ad Network Privacy Policy

**Last Updated: February 10,2009**

This Privacy Policy sets forth the Travel Ad Network ("TAN'") policy with respect to the Personally Identifiable Information ("PII") and Non-Personally Identifiable Information ("Non-PII") that is collected from users ("Users") of TAN websites (collectively, the "Sites"). By voluntarily providing us with your PII, you are consenting to our use of it in accordance with this Privacy Policy including transfer of your PII to TAN and authorized third parties located in the United States and in other countries. 

#### COLLECTION OF PII

When you register or subscribe to our newsletters, and/or participate in activities on the Sites such as forums, message boards, rating articles or completing questionnaires, TAN will collect PII including, for example, your full name, email address zip code, gender, age and similar information. 

#### COLLECTION OF NON-PII

We collect Non-PII, such as IP addresses and web site usage information, from you when you visit the Sites, using cookies and other technologies. 

**Cookies**. Cookies are unique alphanumeric codes that web sites place on your web browser. We use cookies and the Non-PII collected to, among other things, facilitate our login processes; allow you to personalize and store your settings; collect usage information; determine our total audience size and traffic; and help us improve our Sites by measuring which areas are of greatest interest to users. We may also permit third parties to use cookies on our Sites. 

Each time we display online advertisements to you, we also use cookies to recognize your computer. Because we may serve advertisements on many different Web sites through the TAN advertising network, we are able to compile Non-PII over time about where you, or others who are using your computer, saw and/or clicked on the advertisements we display. We use this Non-PII to make predictions about your characteristics, interests or preferences and to display targeted advertisements that we believe may be of interest to you. We may also associate this Non-PII with you during subsequent visits, purchases or other activity on participating advertisers' Web sites in order to determine the effectiveness of the advertisements. 

You can set the browser on your computer to warn you each time a cookie is being sent, block third party cookies or block all cookies. However, by blocking all cookies you may not have access to certain features on our Sites. 

We also use web beacons (invisible images often referred to as pixel tags or clear GIFs) on our Sites in order to recognize users and assess traffic patterns, and we may include web beacons and cookies in our e-mail messages in order to count how many e-mail messages have been opened. 

#### HOW WE USE YOUR PII

TAN may use your PII for the purposes for which you specifically provided it via the Sites including, without limitation, enabling TAN to process and fulfill your subscription or other requests.

In addition, TAN may use your PII to: 

  *  Send you information about your relationship or transactions with us.
  *  Notify you about our products, services, and special offers.
  *  Contact you with information from TAN and third parties that we believe will be of interest to you.
  *  Enhance or develop features, products and services for the Sites.
  *  Provide advertisers and other third parties with aggregate information about you, our web site user base and usage patterns.
  *  Personalize the content and advertising that you and others see on our Sites.
  *  Allow third parties to send you promotional materials about their products and services.
  *  Share your PII with TAN affiliated companies and businesses.
  *  Disclose to TAN's third party service providers solely for the purpose of providing such services including, without limitation, facilitating some aspects of our Sites, sending e-mail, and fulfilling purchase requests.
  *  In response to a subpoena or similar investigative demand, a court order, or other request from a law enforcement or government agency; to establish or exercise our legal rights; to defend against legal claims; or as otherwise required by law.
  *  In connection with efforts to investigate, prevent, or take other action regarding illegal activity, suspected fraud or other wrongdoing; to protect and defend the rights, property or safety of our company, our users, our employees, or others; to comply with applicable law or cooperate with law enforcement; or to enforce our Sites' terms and conditions or other agreements or policies.
  *  In connection with a corporate transaction, such as the sale of all or a portion of our business, a divestiture, merger, consolidation, or asset sale, or in the unlikely event of bankruptcy.

**Integrating PII with Non-PII**. We may combine the PII and Non-PII that we collect from you on the Sites with other information that you provide to us in connection with your use of other TAN products, services and Sites, and/or information we collect from third parties, and we reserve the right to license, rent, sell or otherwise use such combined information. 

**Third Party Sites.** As a service to our Users, the Sites may include links to other sites ('Third Party Sites"). This Privacy Policy applies only to the Sites and not to any Third Party Sites. ONCE YOU LEAVE OUR SITES, WE ARE NO LONGER RESPONSIBLE. We suggest contacting the Third Party Sites directly for information on their privacy, security, data collection and distribution policies. 

**Unsolicited Information**. This Privacy Policy does not apply to any unsolicited information that you voluntarily provide while visiting the Sites. You may provide information while using certain features of the Sites such as forums, message boards, chats, creating community profiles, and rating, tagging and commenting on articles. When you use these features you should be aware that any information you submit, including your name, location and e-mail address, is publicly available to any visitor to the applicable Site. 

We are not responsible for any information you choose to submit through these interactive features. Also, whenever you voluntarily disclose personal information on publicly-viewable web pages, that information can be collected and used by others. For example, if you post your email address, you may receive unsolicited messages. TAN cannot control who reads your posting or what other users may do with the information you voluntarily post, so we encourage you to exercise discretion and caution with respect to your personal information. 

When an individual chooses to post information that will be publicly disclosed, he or she is responsible for ensuring that such information conforms to all local data protection laws. We are not responsible under any data protection laws for User posted information. 

**Children.** TAN does not knowingly collect personal data from children under the age of 13 through the Sites. If you are under thirteen, please do not give us any Personally Identifiable Information. We encourage parents and legal guardians to monitor their children's Internet usage and to help enforce our Privacy Policy by instructing their children to never provide Personally Identifiable Information on the Sites without their permission. If you have reason to believe that a child under the age of 13 has provided Personally Identifiable Information to TAN through the Sites, please contact us, and we will endeavor to delete that information from our databases. 

**Security**. We take commercially reasonable steps to protect Personally Identifiable Information provided to the Sites and to protect such information from loss, misuse, and unauthorized access, disclosure, alteration, or destruction. However, no Internet or e-mail transmission is ever fully secure or error free. In particular, e-mail sent to or from the Sites may not be secure, and you should therefore take special care in deciding what information you send to us via e-mail. Please keep this in mind when disclosing any Personally Identifiable Information to TAN or to any other party via the Internet. 

### Other Terms and Conditions

#### HOW TO ACCESS YOUR INFORMATION

You can also review and update your PII by contacting us at the email address provided below in the "How to contact us" section of this Privacy Policy or at [http://travelad.listrak.com](http://travelad.listrak.com/). 

#### HOW WE PROTECT YOUR INFORMATION

We use commercially reasonable administrative, technical, personnel and physical measures to safeguard PII in our possession against loss, theft and unauthorized use, disclosure or modification. 

#### CHANGES TO OUR PRIVACY POLICY

From time to time we may revise this Privacy Policy. If we make revisions that change the way we collect or use your PII, those changes will be posted in this Privacy Policy and the effective date will be noted at the beginning of the Policy. Therefore, you should review it periodically so that you are up to date on our most current policies and practices. If you use the Sites after we post changes to the Privacy Policy, you will be deemed to have accepted the modified Privacy Policy. 

#### CHOICE

**Cookie Opt Out**. To visit the TAN opt out, go to [http://privacy.traveladnetwork.com/optout ](http://privacy.traveladvertising.com/OptOut.aspx)

To visit the Atlas (Microsoft Advertising) opt out, go to <http://www.atlassolutions.com/optout.aspx>. 

To opt-out of other cookies, or if you would like more information about this practice, please visit the Network Advertising Initiative, an organization championing consumer privacy and establishing advertising standards, at this URL: [](http://www.networkadvertising.org/optout_nonppii.asp)<http://www.networkadvertising.org/optout_nonppii.asp>

**PII Opt-Out.** To opt out of our use of your PII, you may (a) click the appropriate "Opt Out" link in any applicable e-mail communication or newsletter or (b) visit [http://travelad.listrak.com](http://www.traveladnetwork.com/content/view/70).  

E-mails that are sent to you as a result of you performing a business transaction with us or requesting specific information from the Sites are not subject to an Opt Out process. If you have any suggestions on how to improve these e-mails, please communicate to our Customer Service group using the Contact Us functionality on the applicable Site. 

#### HOW TO CONTACT US

If you have any questions, comments or concerns about our Privacy Policy, you may contact us at [privacy@traveladnetwork.com.](mailto:privacy@traveladnetwork.com.)
